Guide to the Full Frame Archive Collection, 1998-2017 RL.00424
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Full Frame Film Festival, 2005
  - Wetback: The Undocumented Documentary (2004)
    Wetback follows undocumented migrant workers from their home in Nicaragua across Central America and Mexico to the U.S.-Mexican border, meeting many other migrants along the way. They encounter gangs, vigilantes, corrupt law enforcement, physical danger, and safe havens in their attempt to be among the 10% of migrants who actually make it all the way into North America. The migrants, those who aid them, and those who turn them back all give their own perspectives on how this vast, illegal system trafficking in cheap labor and dreams actually functions, and what its terrible costs and perils are.
    In Spanish and English with English subtitles
    - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, TRT 92:00 (Box 7)
    - DVD master, TRT 92:00 (Box 8)
    - DVD use copy (Box 11)
  - After Innocence (2005)
    Director: Jessica Sanders
    Producer: Jessica Sanders and Marc Simon
    Award won: Full Frame content + intent = change
    TRT: 95:00
    During the 1990s and 2000s, a growing number of convicted felons were exonerated by DNA evidence as its use increased-more than 150 by 2005. But establishing their innocence is only the beginning of the story. Once released, they face the challenges of returning to their families and too society-often with their criminal records left intact and no apology for their false imprisonment. This film follows seven such exonerees through their difficult transitions to life on the outside, as they pursue new goals and transform themselves.
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 FLAT Dolby SRD, reel 1 of 5, 1710 ft. (Reel 104)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 FLAT Dolby SRD, reel 2 of 5, 1710 ft. (Reel 105)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 FLAT Dolby SRD, reel 3 of 5, 1710 ft. (Reel 106)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 FLAT Dolby SRD, reel 4 of 5, 1710 ft. (Reel 107)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 FLAT Dolby SRD, reel 5 of 5, 1710 ft. (Reel 108)
    - DVD master, TRT 95:00 (Box 8)
    - DVD use copy (Box 11)
  - Festival materials, 2005
    - Tote bags, t-shirts, and lanyards, 2005; 2 shirts, 2 bags, lanyards and passes (Box 15)
    - Posters, 2005; 5 posters; 1 foam core poster (Box 19)
- Full Frame Film Festival, 2006
  - Iraq in Fragments (2006)
    Director: James Longley
    Producer: John Sinno
    An poetic opus in three parts, this film presents three distinct stories, regions and cinematic styles: A child is apprenticed to the domineering owner of a Baghdad garage; Sadr followers in two Shiite cities rally for regional elections while violently enforcing Islamic law; a family of Kurdish farmers welcomes the U.S. presence, which brings them a measure of new freedom. Longley spent more than two years filming in Iraq before it became too dangerous for Western filmmakers to be there.
    In Arabic and Kurdish with English subtitles
    Use Copies: DVD use copy and special features DVD available.
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 FLAT Dolby SRD, reel 1 of 5, 1656 ft. (Reel 14)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 FLAT Dolby SRD, reel 2 of 5, 1656 ft. (Reel 15)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 FLAT Dolby SRD, reel 3 of 5, 1656 ft. (Reel 16)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 FLAT Dolby SRD, reel 4 of 5, 1656 ft. (Reel 17)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 FLAT Dolby SRD, reel 5 of 5, 1656 ft. (Reel 18)
    - DVD master, TRT 92:00 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 11)
  - The Trials of Darryl Hunt (2005)
    Directors: Ricki Stern and Annie Sundberg
    Producers: Ricki Stern and Annie Sundberg
    TRT: 107:00
    Accused of raping and murdering a young white newspaper reporter in 1984, Hunt was at age 19 convicted by an all-white jury, despite the fact that no physical evidence linked him to the crime. Sentenced to life in prison, Hunt was finally cleared of the crime in 1994 when DNA testing proved his innocence, yet was not released until 2004. In a country that boasts a system of blind justice for all, Darryl Hunt's story speaks to the fear and racism that continue to define communities throughout the nation.
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 1 of 6, 1605 ft. (Reel 19)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 2 of 6, 1605 ft. (Reel 20)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 3 of 6, 1605 ft. (Reel 21)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 4 of 6, 1605 ft. (Reel 22)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 5 of 6, 1605 ft. (Reel 23)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 6 of 6, 1605 ft. (Reel 24)
    - DVD master, TRT 107:00 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 11)
  - No Umbrella: Election Day in the City (2006)
    Director: Laura Paglin
    Producer: Laura Paglin
    TRT: 25:45
    This film looks at the 2004 Election Day failures in one of Cleveland, Ohio's poorest neighborhoods. In the most hotly contested state in the country, gridlock at inner city polls ignites tempers and sets off charges of conspiracy-Paglin drops us squarely into the chaos, observing the irascible octogenarian councilwoman Ms. Fannie Lewis as she takes on polling place breakdowns, an unresponsive bureaucracy and an increasingly agitated electorate.
    - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, TRT 25:45 (Box 1)
    - DVD master, TRT 25:45 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 11)
  - Refugee All Stars (2005)
    Directors: Zach Niles and Banker White
    Producers: Zach Niles and Banker White
    Country: Guinea
    Awards won: Center for Documentary Studies Filmmaker Award and the Full Frame/Emerging Pictures Audience Award
    TRT: 94:00
    Sierra Leone's civil war (1991-2002) displaced hundreds of thousands of people, mostly to refugee camps in Guinea. Seeking to rebuild relationships and express the emotions engendered by the war and devastation, Reuben Koroma, Francis Franco Langba, Efuah Grace, Mohammed Bangura, Arahim Kamara and Alhadji Black Nature Kamara formed an Afro-pop band, the Refugee All-Stars. Their songs bring solace to their countrymen and help the musicians to survive in the post-civil war landscape of their homeland. Compelling personal stories and the infectious music itself suffuse this look at a band of survivors determined to use music to establish a new community.
    In English and local languages with English subtitles
    - Preservation tape master, HDCam, TRT 94:00 (Box 3)
    - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, TRT 94:00 (Box 3)
    - DVD master, TRT 94:00 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 11)
  - I for India (2005)
    Director: Sandhya Suri
    Producers: Carlo Cresto-Dina and Thomas Kufus
    A bittersweet time capsule of alienation, discovery, racism and belonging, this is a chronicle of immigration in Britain, as seen through the eyes of one Asian family and their movie camera. In 1965, Yash Pal Suri left India to pursue his medical studies in England. He immediately bought two sets of home movie equipment; one he sent to his family in India, and the other he kept for himself. For forty years, this extended family exchanged "cine-letters," chronicling their daily lives.
    In Hindi and English, with English subtitles
    - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, TRT 70:00 (Box 2)
    - DVD master, TRT 70:00 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 11)
  - Sir! No Sir! (2005)
    Director: David Zeiger
    Producer: David Zeiger
    Award won: Seeds of War
    TRT: 83:29
    This film tells the long suppressed story of the GI movement to end the war in Vietnam. Contrary to the popular image of long-haired hippies spitting on returning soldiers, this account vividly demonstrates that GIs, for whom it was a life-and-death issue, were at the heart of the anti-war movement. Narrated by veteran GI resisters recalling peace marches and stiff jail sentences, it deals with racial politics, class and personal responsibility, challenging us to re-examine our received history of the Vietnam War.
    - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, TRT 83:29 (Box 3)
    - DVD master, TRT 83:29 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 11)
  - Workingman's Death (2005)
    Director: Michael Glawogger
    Producers: Erich Lackner, Miriam Quinte, Pepe Danquart
    Country: Austria
    TRT: 122:00
    Has manual labor disappeared in the twenty-first century, or has it just become invisible? This film presents five portraits of extreme physical labor under dangerous conditions around the world: illegal coal mining in the Ukraine's Donbass Basin; sulfur mining on Kawah Ijen, Indonesia; livestock slaughtering in Port Harcourt, Nigeria; shipbreaking in Gaddani Pakistan, and steel smelting in Liaoning, China. In-depth interviews with the workers reveal both the hardships and injustices they experience, as well as the pride they find in their work. An epilogue visits a former steelworks in Germany, now a theme park and site for public art. The film is scored by John Zorn. Contains graphic images related to animal slaughter.
    In Russian, Bahasa Indonesia, English, Ibu, Yoruba, Pashtu, Mandarin Chinese, and German. DVD use copy has subtitles in English and several other languages.
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 FLAT Dolby SRD, reel 1 of 7, 1569 ft. (Reel 77)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 FLAT Dolby SRD, reel 2 of 7, 1569 ft. (Reel 78)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 FLAT Dolby SRD, reel 3 of 7, 1569 ft. (Reel 79)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 FLAT Dolby SRD, reel 4 of 7, 1569 ft. (Reel 80)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 FLAT Dolby SRD, reel 5 of 7, 1569 ft. (Reel 81)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 FLAT Dolby SRD, reel 6 of 7, 1569 ft. (Reel 82)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 FLAT Dolby SRD, reel 7 of 7, 1569 ft. (Reel 83)
    - Data CD: English subtitles (stl), [[extent?]] (Box 4)
    - DVD master, TRT 122:00 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 11)
  - My Country, My Country (2006)
    Director: Laura Poitras
    Producers: Laura Poitras and Jocelyn Glatzer
    Award won: Full Frame Inspiration Award
    Poitras follows Iraqi physician Dr. Riyadh, father of six and Sunni political candidate, through the eight months leading up to Iraq's first elections after the fall of Sadaam Hussein. An outspoken critic of the occupation, Dr. Riyadh is passionate about building democracy in his country. The film interweaves into Riyadh's story the U.S. military, Australian private security contractors, and the U.N. officials who orchestrated the elections, invoking heartbreaking questions about democracy, the legitimacy of elections and the unpredictable will of an occupied people.
    In Arabic, English and Kurdish, with English subtitles
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 FLAT Dolby SRD, reel 1 of 5, 1710 ft. (Reel 25)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 FLAT Dolby SRD, reel 2 of 5, 1710 ft. (Reel 26)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 FLAT Dolby SRD, reel 3 of 5, 1710 ft. (Reel 27)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 FLAT Dolby SRD, reel 4 of 5, 1710 ft. (Box 28)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 FLAT Dolby SRD, reel 5 of 5, 1710 ft. (Reel 29)
    - DVD master, TRT 95:00 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 11)
  - The Intimacy of Strangers (2005)
    Director: Eva Weber
    Producers: Samantha Zarzosa, Danielle Green, Katherine Armfelt
    Award won: Full Frame President's Award
    TRT: 19:35
    Cell phone conversations have the ability to collapse the distinctions between public and private space. In these conversations, intimate moments are performed for strangers in public spaces and director Eva Weber captures these moments, recording cell phone conversations in the public sphere. The film weaves these seemingly unrelated conversations into a cohesive documentary narrative.
    - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, TRT 19:35 (Box 1)
    - DVD master, TRT 19:35 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 11)
  - Rain in a Dry Land (2006)
    Director: Anne Makepeace
    Producer: Anne Makepeace
    Award won: Full Frame/Working Films Award
    TRT: 82:36
    This film follows two Bantu families, displaced by the Somalian civil war, as they journey from a refugee camp in Kenya to the U.S. They struggle with the seemingly impossible tasks of daily life in America-supporting a family, learning English, and applying rural skills to an unfamiliar urban lifestyle. Both families seek a balance between a way of life they know and trust and their new place in America, reconciling their dreams of the land of freedom with the puzzling and difficult reality.
    In Somali, Mai Mai and English, with English subtitles
    - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, TRT 82:36 (Box 2)
    - DVD master, TRT 82:36 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 11)
  - Festival materials, 2006
    - Program Book (Box 6)
    - T-shirts, messenger bag, 2006; 5 shirts; 1 bag (Box 15)
    - Programs and maps, 2006 (Box 15)
- Full Frame Film Festival, 2007
  - War Dance (2006)
    Director: Sean Fine and Andrea Nix Fine
    Producer: Albie Hecht
    TRT: 105:00
    A group of Acholi children in Northern Uganda's Patongo refugee camp prepares a music and dance performance to compete in Uganda's annual National Kampala Music Festival. Northern Uganda has been at war for over twenty years with the rebel group Lord's Resistance Army, which abducts children as young as five to join their ranks. Several children share accounts of devastated lives, assaulted bodies, and lost family members. This compassionate film reveals the hope, peace and even joy the children find in music and dance, soothing the wounds of war.
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 1 of 6, 1575 ft. (Reel 114)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 2 of 6, 1575 ft. (Reel 115)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 3 of 6, 1575 ft. (Reel 116)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 4 of 6, 1575 ft. (Reel 117)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 5 of 6, 1575 ft. (Reel 118)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 6 of 6, 1575 ft. (Reel 119)
    - DVD master, TRT 107:00 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 11)
  - The Monastery: Mr. Vig and the Nun (2006)
    Director: Pernille Rose Grønkjær
    Producer: Michael Fleischer [exec prod]
    Country: Denmark
    Awards won: Full Frame Grand Jury Award and Charles E. Guggenheim Emerging Artist Award
    Alternately bemused, confused and fussy, Mr. Vig gives his Danish castle to the Russian Orthodox Church for a monastery. When the church accepts and sends a nun to seal the deal, Mr. Vig finds out there'll have to be a few changes around the house. A beautifully shot and witty meditation on the peevish merging of life and faith.
    In English, Danish and Russian with English subtitles
    - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, TRT 85:00 (Box 2)
    - DVD master, TRT 85:00 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 11)
  - Cross Your Eyes Keep Them Wide (2006)
    Director: Ben Wu
    Producer: Ben Wu
    TRT: 23:00
    This film is a meditative portrait of a group of artists at San Francisco's "Creativity Explored," a work space for artists with developmental disabilities. In their own words, the artists discuss their work, the difficulties they face in the world, and the safe, and often surprising community they've formed within the studio walls. Wu presents a celebration of human imagination.
    - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, TRT 23:00 (Box 1)
    - DVD master, TRT 23:00 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 11)
  - Ari no Heitai (The Ants) (2005)
    English title: The Ants
    Director: IKEYA Kaoru
    Producer: GON Yoko
    Country: Japan
    TRT: 101:20
    Waichi Okumura was an "ant soldier" in the Japanese military, one who performed the lowest and dirtiest jobs in World War II. After Japan's surrender, he and 2600 other soldiers were ordered to stay behind to fight in China's civil war, not returning home until 1954. Now 80, he insists on clearing the record with the Japanese government, which claims that these soldiers volunteered to stay behind. Okumura returns to the killing fields in Shanxi Province and meets some of his former enemies. This film portrays the moral conviction of a man abandoned by his country after he had been taught to kill for it.
    In Japanese and Chinese with English subtitles
    - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, TRT 101:20 (Box 2)
    - DVD master, TRT 101:20 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 11)
  - Angels in the Dust (2007)
    Director: Louise Hogarth
    Producer: Diane Weyermann [exec prod]
    TRT: 96:00
    Bothshabelo is a village, a school, and an orphanage, providing sanctuary to hundreds of South Africans marginalized by race, class, sexual assault and the effects of the prevailing AIDS epidemic. This film tells the story of Marion Cloete, who traded in a cushy upper class lifestyle in Johannesburg to found it, and the people she cares for. A visual intervention in a nation overwhelmed by rape, violence, HIV/AIDS, and the legacy of Apartheid, this film offers a pathway of hope.
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 FLAT Dolby SR, reel 1 of 6, 1440 ft. (Reel 30)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 FLAT Dolby SR, reel 2 of 6, 1440 ft. (Reel 31)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 FLAT Dolby SR, reel 3 of 6, 1440 ft. (Reel 32)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 FLAT Dolby SR, reel 4 of 6, 1440 ft. (Reel 33)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 FLAT Dolby SR, reel 5 of 6, 1440 ft. (Reel 34)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 FLAT Dolby SR, reel 6 of 6, 1440 ft. (Reel 35)
    - DVD master, TRT 96:00 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 11)
  - The Devil Came on Horseback (2007)
    Producers: Annie Sundberg, Ricki Stern, Jane Wells, Gretchen Wallace
    Awards won: Full Frame/Working Films Award and the Seeds of War
    TRT: 87:00
    An up-close and uncompromising look at the crisis in Darfur, this film exposes the ongoing tragedy in Sudan as seen through the eyes of one American witness, former U.S. Marine Captain Brian Steidle, an official military observer. Armed with just a camera, paper and pen, but with access far beyond that of a journalist, Steidle's photographs and testimony reveal a genocide that had by 2007 claimed over 400,000 lives. The film presents the historical and economic basis for the Sudanese government's support and encouragement of the atrocities, alongside UN and US debates on the definition of "genocide," as millions of people suffer.
    In Arabic and English with English subtitles
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 1 of 5, 1566 ft. (Reel 36)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 2 of 5, 1566 ft. (Reel 37)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 3 of 5, 1566 ft. (Reel 38)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 4 of 5, 1566 ft. (Reel 39)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 5 of 5, 1566 ft. (Reel 40)
    - DVD master, TRT 87:00 (Box 4, Box 11)
  - Uganda Rising (2006)
    Directors: Jesse James Miller and Pete McCormack
    Producer: Alison Lawton
    TRT: 82:00
    For two decades, the Acholi people of Northern Uganda have been caught in a civil war between a rebel group whose main objective is inhumane terror and a government whose military response has often increased suffering. Over 1.5 million people have been displaced into camps and over 25,000 children have been abducted as soldiers and sex slaves. Against this backdrop, children who have never known peace live as if they still believe in the future. The embodiment of resilience and hope, this film tells their story, and that of Uganda's fight to be free.
    English and Acholi with English subtitles
    - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, TRT 82:00 (Box 3)
    - DVD master, TRT 82:00 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - Forever (2006)
    Director: Heddy Honigmann
    Producer: Carmen Cobos
    Cimetière du Père-Lachaise, one of Paris's largest cemeteries, is the final resting place of many great artists, writers and composers of the nineteenth and twentieth century. Heddy Honigmann observes the visitors that come each day to pay their respects and asks them why they have come; some, she follows into their own creative lives in the city. A Japanese pianist rehearses Chopin and seeks inspiration from his grave; an Iranian singer finds resonance in the novels of his compatriot Sadegh Hedayat; an embalmer admires Modigliani's gift for portraiture; and a succession of avid readers pay homage to Marcel Proust. Others come to mourn their loved ones, or simply to meditate on mortality. The film is a pensive reflection on the power of art to move and inspire us "forever."
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 1 of 6, 1425 ft. (Reel 120)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 2 of 6, 1425 ft. (Reel 121)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 3 of 6, 1425 ft. (Reel 122)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 4 of 6, 1425 ft. (Reel 123)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 5 of 6, 1425 ft. (Reel 124)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 6 of 6, 1425 ft. (Reel 125)
    - DVD master, TRT 95:00 (Box 8)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - Lumo (2007)
    Directors: Bent-Jorgen Perlmutt and Nelson Walker III
    Producers: Louis Abelman, Ben-Jorgen Perlmutt, and Nelson Walker III
    TRT: 72:00
    Lumo Sinai was just over 20 when marauding soldiers attacked her in the eastern Congo. A fistula, a medical condition common among victims of violent rape, rendered Lumo incontinent and threatens her ability to bear children. Rejected by her fiancé and cast aside by her family, she awaits reconstructive surgery at HEAL Africa Hospital. This cinema verité film looks at this war torn region where rape is commonly used as a weapon of war.
    In French, Swahili and local languages, with English subtitles
    - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, TRT 72:00 (Box 2)
    - DVD master, TRT 72:00 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - Banished (2007)
    Director: Marco Williams
    Producers: Two Tone Productions and the Center for Investigative Reporting
    Banished examines the legacy of racial cleansing incidents that occurred in communities scattered throughout the United States in the early twentieth century, when violent mobs forced thousands of African-American families to abandon their homes. Three communities are profiled, each approaching the challenge of reconciliation differently. In Forsyth County, Georgia, an African-American family seeks compensation for their lost land, legally transferred to white ownership by "adverse possession; a reconciliation committee stalemates. Descendants of a family banished from Pierce City, Missouri, retrieve their great-grandfather's remains and ask the city to cover the cost. Harrison, Arkansas, is divided between those who would make amends for their town's racist past and those who are drawn to its lack of black people. The film raises broader questions about how past wrongs can or cannot be redressed, by whom, and through what acts.
    - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, TRT 88:00 (Box 10)
    - DVD master, TRT 88:00 (Box 8)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - For the Bible Tells Me So (2007)
    Director: Daniel Karslake
    Producers: Daniel Karslake, Helen Mendoza, and Nancy Kennedy
    Award won: Kathleen Bryan Edwards Award for Human Rights
    TRT: 97:00